# **HENRY HEIN**

#### FRONT END DEVELOPER



Henryhein.hein@gmail.com





www.github.com/henry-hein

henryhein.netlify.app

## **PROFILE**

I'm electronics engineer from Canada with three years of experience seeking a full-time remote **junior** software developer position to extend my knowledge as a lifelong engineer. As part of the effort, I've been learning different programming languages for the past eight months. To help learn new technologies, I've been building a portfolio of projects, which can be seen in the website above.

#### **SKILLS**

- $igode{}$
- HTML5
- Javascript
- JQuerv

- CSS
- Heroku
- Bootstrap

- React
- RESTful API
- Mobile Responsive Design

- GitHub/Git
- UI/UX
- Windows, Mac, Linux OS

- Hardhat
- Solidity
- Testing and Debugging

- Ether.js
- Remix IDE
- Defi, Trading, NFTs, and DAOs

## **EDUCATION**

 $\bullet$ 

#### **Bachelor of Applied Science, Electronics Engineering**

Simon Fraser University / Burnaby Sep 2012 - Dec 2017

#### **PROJECTS**

 $(\bullet)$ 

#### **Front End Web Development**

Self-Learning / August 2021 - Present

Vancouver, Canada

Currently teaching myself how to program websites in HTML, CSS, JS, jQuery Bootstrap, and React. As well as cloud hosting platform like Heroku and version control software such as GitHub.

- Created React mobile responsive League of Legend Champion List web app that pulls data from their API and has search, filter, and carousel functionalities
- Designed and built mobile responsive currency converter that interacts with open source API using React, Bootstrap, CSS, hosted website on Heroku cloud application, and managed versions on Git
- Built movie finder in React and Bootstrap that interacts with open source movie database API and managed versions on Git
- Designed and built mobile responsive personal portfolio website using HTML,
  CSS, Bootstrap, and Git
- Built interactive timer-based math game using Vanilla JS, jQuery, HTML, CSS, and Git Built responsive Apple, Airbnb, and Newsweek website clones using HTML, Bootstrap, and CSS

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Facilities Service Clerk

Vancouver, Canada

Simon Fraser University / Jan 2019 - Dec 2021

Working as part of SFU Surrey Facilities Team to ensure campuses operate smoothly.

- Employed teamwork, problem solving, and analysis skills to handle maintenance requests such as fixing leaks, broken doors, and hanging white boards
- Provided excellent customer service to internal SFU staffs and ensured all requests were handled in timely and respectful manner

#### Electronic Test Engineer

**♥** Vancouver, Canada

Innovative Circuit Technology / Jan 2018 - Dec 2018

Worked as part of R&D Team, responsible for procurement, assembly, testing, documentations, and debugging power electronic systems, which lead to company savings of \$100,000 in six months.

- Created test plans, performed tests, and documented findings for magnetics for power converter systems, which decreased core temperature by 5°C
- Communicated supply chain, manufacturers, engineers, and technicians and components arrived early by average of 1 week
- Debugged and tested new high-power converter under supervision to execute test plans and created test jig that reduced setup time by 10 minutes each test

## Hardware Test Engineer

Vancouver, Canada

TRIUMF / Sep 2016 - Dec 2017

Worked as part of Beamline Diagnostics Team, responsible for procurement, assembly, testing, SPICE simulation, documentations, and debugging beamline electronics.

- Diagnosed, and repaired electronic circuits, assembled mechanical casings, and created cable harnesses which improved assembly time by 5 minutes per unit
- Communicated with PCB manufacturers, component suppliers, and team members to ensure all specifications and components arrived early by average of 4 days

#### **Embedded Systems Integrator**

**♀** Vancouver, Canada

LineSpect / Sep 2015 - Apr 2015

Work at a start-up company in prototyping hexcopter that inspects faults in power line. Was in charge of integrating, troubleshooting, and designing sensor electronics that reads EMF info from power lines

- Characterized Signal to Noise ratio of Ultrasound and Ultraviolet sensors and designed circuits that improved Signal to Noise ratio each sensor by 10%
- Designed and Integrated motors, sensors, antennas, and lithium battery that reduced weight of hexcopter by 10%, which improved flight time by 5%

#### **INTERESTS**

Travelling

Cooking

Basketball

Soccer

Hiking

Kick Boxing